Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]



Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Technical Architecture, Spring, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Maven



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: Mphasis Limited

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Hyderabad

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, Technical Architecture, Spring, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Maven

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

5+ years of relevant experience in Java/J2EE technologies with good

Experience in Object Oriented Programming(oops) and design.

Strong development experience in enterprise Java and Web based technologies.

Extensive development experience in Spring Boot (IOC, JDBC Support, ORM Support, Spring MVC, Transaction management)

Working Knowledge in Restful web services.

Developing & maintaining quality code.

Good debugging and analyzing skills

Helping and resolving technical issues faced by the team.

Strong Verbal and client interaction skills.

Good understanding of design patterns.

Strong analytical and problem-solving skills

Expertise in developing UI using jQuery, AngularJS.

Experience in RDBMS databases like Oracle.

Good at writing SQL queries.

Experience in Collections, Multithreading, Concurrent Programming.

Expertise in java 1.7, familiar and working knowledge of java 1.8 concepts.

Domain experience in Banking, IOT.

Work Experience

Mphasis Limited as Senior Software Engineer Aug 2020 to Till Date

Indecomm Global Services as Senior Software Engineer Apr 2019 to Aug 2020

Brandenburg innovations India Limited as Software Engineer Jul 2018 to Apr 2019

Concentrix Services India Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer Jun 2015 to Jul 2018

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from j.n.t.u anantapur in 2011

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
UBUNTU, windows7	
JAVA	
Spring, Hibernate, Web services	
spring boot	
SQL Developer, SQL Workbench	
WildFly and Apache tomcat	
Perforce and GIT.	
Java script, Html, Angularjs, Angular	
MAVEN	
Eclipse, STS, Intellij	
Oracle, MySql, Cassandra	
AWS, JIRA	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			
Telugu	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time